

PHILLIP KRÜGER

SYSTEMS ARCHITECT, SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Centurion, Gauteng, South Africa phillip.kruger@phillip-kruger.com phillip-kruger.com github.phillip-kruger.com

SKILLS

Java & Java EE

I have been writing Java since the
beginning of Java and still loving it! I stay
up to date with the Language and
specifications. I have extensive
experience in Enterprise Java, including
JAX-RS, JAX-WS, CDI, JAXB, JAXP, XML,
JSON-P, JSON, JPA, JDBC, EJB, JTA, JCA,
JMS, JSF, JSP, Servlets, WebSockets, Bean
Validation, Portlets, Spring, Swagger,
Lombok and much more

Linux

I have been running Linux on my Personal PC since 1999, starting with Mandrake and then basically went through many distributions including Red Hat, OpenSUSE, Debian, PCLinuxOS. I then discovered Gentoo Linux, and went from a basic Desktop user to being comfortable with building my own OS on my PC. I also used Ubuntu and Mint. For the past few years I have been using Arch Linux and loving it. I am comfortable running and managing Linux servers and Docker containers

Tools

I have been using many tools through the years. Currently these are some of my favorites: GIT, Gogs, Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube, Maven, Ansible, Netbeans, Docker

Infrastructure

SUMMARY

I am an accomplished Software **developer** and **architect** offering experience in creating systems in various industries, ranging from banking, insurance, rewards programs, retail and mobile. I have extensive experience in **full stack development**, and prefer to be active in all parts of the SDLC. From conceptualizing to running in production.

I have a passion for clean code and evolutionary architecture. I love Java, Linux and Open source.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MMI Holdings . Multiply

Jan 2015 - Current

Systems Architect

Multiply is a Wellness and Rewards program that encourage clients to live healthier and reach their financial goals.

I am the Systems Architect andI'm responsible for the overall Architecture of the Systems and the Technical implementation and quality of the systems and teams.

I have a hands-on approach and believe in Clean Code Principles and Evolutionary Architecture.

Our systems range from AS400, Java SE and EE, Javascript and wedo a lot of integration to and from Partners and other Product Houses in MMI.

Standard Bank

Jul 2014 - Jan 2015

Software consultant

As a software consultant I assisted with performance tuning of services used by the mobile app. I also assisted with the automation of infrastructure deployment and configuration

Thumbtribe Mobile Solutions

Jun 2008 - Jul 2014

IT Director, Enterprise Architect, Software developer

Thumbtribe was a startup that brought mobile solutions to feature phones, smart phones and the web. We built a platform that can deliver content on feature phones, smart phones, websites and apps via USSD, WAP, HTML and REST services.

I was running everything IT related, from the teams, the infrastructure to the software.

Infowave

Aug 2006 - May 2008

Enterprise Architect

I was responsible for defining and implementing a new Architecture for a custom Financial system that was running in Oracle Forms.

Dariel Solutions

May 2005 - Jul 2006

Software Developer, Technical Team Lead, Architect

I was consulting at Discovery Life, running the dev team, responsible for architecture, design and implementation of new systems.

Software Audits - I was responsible for a two week audit of the South African Post Office Leave Application System

Standard Bank

Feb 2001 - Apr 2005

Java Developer

The CIO of Standard Bank attended our 3rd year project day at University. After seeing my project, he offered me a job. I was part of many teams in the bank, doing Java and Java EE development. I continued my studies part time.

EDUCATION

University of Johannesburg

2001 - 2003

B.Sc (Hons) Computer Science

I enjoy setting up and automating the environments that my systems need to run. MySQL, PostgreSQL, DB2, OpenRDF, Elasticsearch, Wildfly, GlassFish and Payara, TomEE, WAS Liberty, Pluto and

Communication

I enjoy talking and debating about technical concerns. I blog about technical topics and session feedback from conferences. I also enjoy presenting technical topics in forums. I am comfortable running technical meetings and finding solutions around a white board.

Other

I have knowledge of many other languages, frameworks and libraries. I believe in using the right tool for the job and can learn a new specification, language or framework quickly and easily. Some of these include HTML5, CSS3, Sass & Less, JavaScript, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Foundation, PHP, SVG, XSLT, SQL, RDF, SPARQL, Webjars, OPML, ATOM and RSS and more.

MYERS-BRIGGS PSYCHOLOGICAL TYPE

INTJ (introversion, intuition, thinking, judgment)

STRENGTHS

Strategic * Analytical * Achiever * Deliberative * Relator

ACTIVITIES

I enjoy playing squash, both socially and league.

Honors degree in Computer Science, focusing on Security, Web programming, Robotics and Al.

University of Johannesburg

1998 - 2000

B.Sc Information Technology

Major in Computer Science and Informatics.

Solms Training

2000 - 2006

Other courses

Programming in Java, Advanced Java. XML, Object-Oriented Analysis and Design using UML, Enterprise Java Beans, Patterns, Architecture

SOFTWARE

Some open source libraries and examples I create and maintain in my free time:

Apiee - Swagger on Java EE

Stompee - Websockets log file on Java EE

Klokee - Message input on Java EE

PUBLISHED ARTICLES

Some articles from myblog that has been published:

Your own Swagger UI on Liberty

Monkey methodology

Google might be wrong

CONFERENCES ATTENDED

- 2007 Oracle Open World, San Francisco
- 2011 JavaOne, San Francisco
- 2011 Mobile World Congress, Barcelona
- 2015 JavaOne, San Francisco
- 2016 IBM Interconnect, Las Vegas

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Software Development
- System Design
- System Architecture
- Business Design
- Business Architecture
- Technical Writing
- Enterprise Architecture Technical Presentation
- Communication
- Team Leadership
- Research & Analysis
- Process Improvements